infobyip.com 2019-12-17

# Privacy policy

## Introduction

This privacy policy describes how _infobyip.com_ ("We" or "Us") collects, uses, stores and discloses information about you when you use our website, widgets and other online products and services (collectively, the "Services") as well as your rights and choices concerning your information. This Privacy Policy applies whenever you use our "Services". 

## Information we collect and how we collect it

### Information About You That You Share With Us Directly

When you use our Services, you may give us information directly, and we'll store that information on our systems and use it for the purposes described in this Privacy Policy. Examples include but are not limited to: 

  * When contacting us you might be asked to provide your first and last name, email address, emotional state, messages subject and message text and screenshot indicating the issue.

### Information we collect as you use our Services

  * Services you access, views and interactions with content and ads, features you use, actions you take, time, frequency and duration of these activities.
  * Your client IP address, user agent, browser type and settings, operating system, referral URLs, device information, network and connection information.
  * Your search queries and online tool input.
  * Keyboard and mouse activity as you interact with our Services
  * Data from cookies and similar technologies stored on your device

## Cookie and similar technologies

A cookie is a small text file stored in your browser directories. Cookies are created when you visit a website. When you visit a website again cookies are retrieved. Cookies are used to store user settings, login information and other purposes. Some other technologies may also be referred to as cookies if used in a similar manner. 

Below are the categories of cookies used by our services:  | Category| Explanation  
---|---  
Necessary |  This category of cookies are used to provide core website functionality, load balancing, access to secure areas and to combat fraud and abuse. They may also be used for ad frequency capping and aggregated ad reporting. The website or ads cannot properly function without these cookies.   
Preferences |  These cookies are used to remember information that changes the way the site behaves or looks, such as your preferred language, your translation suggestions, the region you are in, font, text size, theme, etc.   
Statistics | These types of cookies are used for reporting and collection of anonymous site usage statistics.  
Marketing | These types of cookies are used to track users across multiple websites with the intention of displaying more relevant and engaging advertisement. When these cookies are disabled users will see non-personalized ads.   
  
You may choose to configure your web browser to refuse cookies. If they do so, note that some parts of our Services may not function properly. You may select the categories of cookies that you allow our Serives to set in cookie settings. If you previously given cookie consent you may withdraw consent. 

## How We Use Information We Collect

  * To provide you with Services you request.
  * To improve and optimize our Services.
  * To respond to your inquires, feedback, comments and concerns.
  * To manage and deliver advertisements.
  * To provide service and ad personalization.
  * To conduct research.
  * To measure performance of our Services.
  * To protect our rights in connection with our Services.
  * To comply with legal obligations.

## How We Disclose Information We collect

### Third party service providers

We will share your information with third-party companies who perform services on our behalf, like payment processing, analytics, hosting services, advertising platforms. 

#### Google Adsense

Third party vendors, including Google, use cookies to serve ads based on a user's prior visits to your website. Google's use of the DoubleClick cookie enables it and its partners to serve ads to your users based on their visit to your sites and/or other sites on the internet. Users may opt out of the use of the DoubleClick cookie for interest-based advertising by visiting [Ad Settings](https://www.google.com/settings/ads). 

#### Google Analytics

You can learn how Google uses data when you use our partners' sites or apps [here](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/). You may opt out from Google Analytics services on this website by disabling Statistics category in cookie settings or via [opt out mechanism](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout) provided by Google. 

#### AddThis

You can opt out fro AddThis processing your data is outlined in [AddThis privacy policy](https://www.oracle.com/legal/privacy/addthis-privacy-policy.html). 

#### CloudFlare

We use CloudFlare for the purposes of content delivery, DDOS mitigation, internet security and distributed DNS services. CloudFlare may set necessary cookies as a part of their service. You can view CloudFlare privacy policy [here](https://www.cloudflare.com/privacypolicy/).

### Safety, Security and Compliance with Law

Your information may be disclosed in following circumstance: 

  * To satisfy any regulation that apply.
  * In response to lawful requests by public authorities.
  * To protect our rights or property
  * To enforce our Terms and Conditions

### Business Transfers

If we sell, buy, merge or transfer ownership of our Services your information may be included among the transferred assets. 

## Third party websites

Users may find advertising or other content on our Site that link to the sites and services of our partners, suppliers, advertisers, sponsors, licensors and other third parties. We do not control the content or links that appear on these sites and are not responsible for the practices employed by websites linked to or from our Site. In addition, these sites or services, including their content and links, may be constantly changing. These sites and services may have their own privacy policies and customer service policies. Browsing and interaction on any other website, including websites which have a link to our Site, is subject to that website's own terms and policies. 

## Do Not Track (DNT)

Our Services do not currently respond to Do Not Track (DNT) browser signal due to lack of industry standardization. 

## Children Under the Age of 13

Our Services are not intended for children under 13 years of age. We do not knowingly collect personal information from children under 13. 

## International data transfers

When you use our Services, your information might be transferred to United States and possibly other countries. 

## How do we protect your data

Your personal data is protected in transit and at rest using reasonable and appropriate security measures. Specific measures depend on the sensitivity of the data. 

## How long do we retain your data

The retention period depends on the reasons why the data was collected and how it is used. We will not retain your personal information longer than necessary for the business purposes stated in this policy or required by law. 

## Changes to this privacy policy

Site has the discretion to update this privacy policy at any time. When we do, we will revise the updated date at the bottom of this page. We encourage Users to frequently check this page for any changes to stay informed about how we are helping to protect the personal information we collect. You acknowledge and agree that it is your responsibility to review this privacy policy periodically and become aware of modifications. 

## Your acceptance of these terms

By using our Services, you signify your acceptance of this policy. If you do not agree to this policy, please do not use our Services. Your continued use of the Services following the posting of changes to this policy will be deemed your acceptance of those changes. 

## Contacting us

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy please contact us at [support@infobyip.com](mail:support@infobyip.com). 

This document was last updated on Dec 1, 2019.
